

# Ajay Singh

Sales Manager

Experienced Sales Manager with over 25 years of proven success in sales and marketing across B2B and B2C sectors. Specializing in Pharma Generic, OTC and FMCG, adept at executing and managing sales and distribution strategies on a pan India scale. Recognized for driving substantial growth and exceeding targets through strategic planning and effective leadership.

xajay9777@gmail.com

H. No 5 Amarnath Colony Kolar Road Bhopal, Bhopal,

in linkedin.com/in/ajay-singh-6158a9226

7049006789

29 July, 1971

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Consultant (NSM)

Dhanwantri Pharmaceutical Pvt.Ltd.

2024 - Present

## Senior Manager

Novita Healthcare Pvt.Ltd.

2022 - 2024

## **Zonal Sales Manager**

Population Services International IPL

07/2016 - 08/2020

## **Regional Business Manager**

Population Services International

01/2011 - 06/2016

#### **Area Sales Manager**

Population Services International

01/2012 - 05/2016

#### Area Sales Manager (Rajasthan)

Population Services International

04/2008

#### Area Sales Manager (Uttar Pradesh)

Population Services International

06/2003

#### Area Sales Manager (chhattisgarh)

Population Services International

11/2000

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Winer of PSI Awards

Sales Achiever of the Year

Sales Excellence Award

Market Penetration Award

Regional Sales Champion Award

Lifetime Achievement Award in Sales

#### **SKILLS**

Strategic Planning

Leadership

Sales Management

istribution Management

Negotiation Skills

Adaptability

Problem-Solving

## **AREA OF EXPOSURE / EXPERTISE**

#### Retail Management

- Handled and facilitate business under Pharma Generic/ FMCG / OTC marketing. under chemist or non-chemist category for urban & rural marketing of more than Rs. 50 Cr. Per Year
- Strong knowledge or specialist of stock / products inventory management, Consumer marketing / retail marketing (Pharma Generic,FMCG & OTC), supply chain management, logistic knowledge and handled more than 25+ super stockiest and C&F's business partners at UP, BR, JHK, MP, CG, RAJ, Haryana, Maharashtra, Katakana, Punjab, HP, J&K, Gujarat and Chandigarhar.

#### Operations Management

 Independent responsible for Territory operations including HR, Finance and sales and marketing, ADMIN for PAN India

#### Man Management

 Handled more than 30 manager and 200+ ground level sales professionals for marketing / business outcomes, good in human handling / man management.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### MBA (Sales and Marketing)

Alagappa University

#### **B.Com**

Barkatullah University Bhopal

#### **TRAINING**

Finance and Accounts

Marketing and Leader Ship Training

Urban and Rural Marketing

Seven Habits

Human Resource Management